Let's now talk about navigation.
接下来让我们学习导航相关的知识
What is navigation?
什么是导航 ?
Why is it important in the context of websites?
为什么导航在网站中起着重要的作用 ?
And how do we provide navigation within our website hierarchy for
以及我们应该如何在我们的网站中
visitors to our website?
恰当地加进一个导航 ?
When we look at many websites out there,
当我们访问当今的网站的时候
we immediately realize that most websites are not single pages.
我们通常马上就会发现 该网站不只由一个网页组成
Of course, you do see occasional single-page websites, too.
当然了 有时你可能也会见到 只有单一页面的网站
But in general, most websites typically consist of multiple pages.
但是大体上来说 网站都是 由若干个网页组成的
And so when a visitor comes to your main web page, typically indexed .html,
所以当访问者访问你的主页 一般来说是 index.html 后
they might also need to navigate to other pages within your website.
他们可能需要从你的主页上 导航到你网站的其它地方
And when they do so, you should have a way of indicating to them which other pages
所以你需要告诉他们 你的网站 还有哪些页面
are there on your website, and also if they move to another page,
以及如果他们导航到了哪些页面
where they are within your web page hierarchy on your website, and
你需要告诉他们 他们当前访问的页面 位于你网站的哪个层次
also an easy way of returning to the main page of your website.
你还需要提供他们一个能够 简单回到主页的方法
All these features can be provided through various navigational
所有这些功能加在一起
aids that you can build into your websites.
方为一个大体合格的导航
Now there are several commonly used navigation patterns
事实上 导航的实现是有一定套路的
that are used extensively on most websites.
就当今时代来说 就有好几种套路 被广泛地应用在各个网站中
In particular, navigation bar is an easy way of providing
不过有一点是共通的 那就是 导航栏通常是让用户
the user with access to the hierarchy of a website.
轻易理清你网站层次结构的一个工具
When you think about website navigation, one of the important features that you
所以当你考虑实现网站导航时 你需关注的一大特征
should consider is the information architecture that you use in your website.
就是是用怎样的信息架构
What exactly is information architecture?
什么叫信息架构 ?
This has to deal with the organization, the labeling,
它包括但不限于考虑如何组织 如何打标签
and the appropriate navigation methods that you provide through
以及使用何种的导航方法
the information that is available on your website.
来引导访问者访问你网站的信息
Now, information architecture design is a whole field in itself.
如今 信息架构的设计 已经是一个独立的领域了
And that is beyond the scope of this course.
而且那超出了本课程的授课范围
But I have provided you with some additional links in the resources,
不过我提供了相关知识的链接
where you can go and explore more details about information architecture.
如果你对信息架构感兴趣 你可以通过那些链接自己学习一下
In particular, we need to consider information
但需要注意的是 当我们设计网站时
architecture when we are designing websites, and
对信息架构的考虑是不可避免的
that also suggests what kind of navigation we should provide within our website.
事实上在考虑信息架构的同时 往往实现何种导航这一问题也会被解决
Typically, websites are organized in some kind of a hierarchical fashion.
一般而言 网站都会具有 某种共同的层次结构
You have a top level page from which you might have subpages.
比如这么一个层次结构 在一个最高层的网页之下
And from those, you can go into further down in the hierarchy.
有若干子网页 然后这些子网页 又有若干子网页
You might even have, within a single layer,
然后同一层的网页之间
cross navigation between different entities within that layer.
可能也存在着某种导航关系
So, any navigation scheme that you design should be able to accommodate all
像这些如此普遍的层次关系 在你设计导航样式时
these different patterns of access to these different
是一定要考虑到
objects of information within your web page.
并且一般而言 是要实现 这些层次结构所对应的导航关系的
In general, most websites will have a navigation bar
总之 大多数网站都会有一个导航栏
designed and available within the web pages of the website.
这个导航栏会出现在该网站的 任一个网页中
The navigation bar is typically shown either at the top or
其出现的位置 则通常是在该网页的
at the bottom of the website.
抬头处或页尾处
Sometimes it will be fixed in location, either the top or
有时它会固定在某个地方
the bottom of the window, which is displaying the web page.
有时可能会随着用户的视野而改变其方位
Whatever be the case, a navigation bar has become a de facto standard for
不论如何 设置导航栏已经成为了
providing a way of informing a visitor
犹如约定俗成般的
about various pages that are available within your website and
向访问者呈现网站有哪些资源
how you can navigate from one to another.
以及资源之间的链接关系的方式
In addition, within the navigation bar, you might also indicate
而且导航栏还能告诉用户
where the user currently is within this hierarchy.
当前位于网站的哪个层次
Taking a look at your own course website,
让我们来看看我们的课程页面吧
you will see the provision of a navigation bar within the course website.
你可以看到这里提供了一个导航
In this case, it is provided more like a sidebar.
不过在这里 导航被设计得 更像是一个侧边栏
So you can see that on the left-hand side,
同时在左边这里
you have information like where you are currently at the moment.
你还能知晓你现在在网站的哪个部分
And so for example, right now, we are on the Course Info page of
比如现在 我能从这得知 我正在浏览该课程的
our course website.
课程信息部分
There are a few suggestions on how to design a good navigation bar.
关于如何设计一个好的导航栏 有许多不同的建议
Here, I have a small list of them.
在这我列举了其中的一些
Of course, non-exhaustive list, so you might have more things to consider
当然了 像这样的建议 其实是不胜枚举的
when you are actually applying a navigation bar to your own website.
当你在你自己的网站中实现导航栏时 你需要考虑的东西往往更多
But when you design navigation, you should typically provide
但是有一点是总要注意的 那就是当你设计导航时
user-friendly terms, but list it within your navigation bar.
你要让其对用户足够友好
And also, you have to standardize the navigation.
同时 你需要架构好你的导航框架
So no matter which page they user is at the moment,
从而无论用户处于你网站的哪个页面
they will still be able to navigate to any other location within your website.
他都能被导航到你网站的其它地方
And also,
同时还要ｇａｏｓｕｙｏｎｇｈｕ
some way of identifying where within the hierarchy the user currently is.
他当前位于你网站的哪个层次
So you might highlight the current page that the user is viewing in the navigation
为做到这点 你可以在你导航栏中
bar, so that it's easy for them to see where they are within the hierarchy.
将当前页面对应的标识高亮
There are some standard web conventions that people use when they
有好几种所谓的"约定俗成"的
design navigation bars.
设计导航栏的套路
One such convention that has been widely adopted
其一是 如果你在你导航栏中 放了你网站的 logo 的话
is that if you put a logo of your website in your navigation bar,
那么当用户点击该 logo 时
clicking on that logo will typically take you back to the home page of that website.
你应该将用户导航至你的主页
Now, some things that you should definitely avoid
然后就是 你需要避免在你的导航栏中
is to have too many items in your navigation bar.
塞进太多的东西
How many is too many?
你可能会问我什么叫太多
If you find it difficult to use your navigation bar, well,
嘛 如果你发现你用导航栏时感到了困难
that is always already too many.
通常就是太多了
It is better to have a smaller subset,
与其事无巨细地将所有东西塞进导航栏
targeted subset, of links within your navigation bar.
不如仔细从中挑选出有意义的链接
Meaningful links, within your navigation bar.
来放进你的导航栏
Again, this is a choice of taste for different people that have different
当然了 这些也只是我的个人偏好 每个人的审美是不一致的
criteria for considering what should and should not be in the navigation bar.
所以关于如何实现导航栏 其实也很难说有个绝对的准则
And also depending on the specific website that has been designed.
而且导航栏的设计 其实也与你网站的属性息息相关
One other thing that you should think about is to avoid generic labels.
另一个需要注意的是 不要在导航栏中泛泛而谈
Things like if you put a product there.
比如你去推销一个产品
What does a product mean?
你需要告诉对方你这产品是干嘛的
Or a service there.
又或你想推销一个服务
What kind of service are you talking about?
那么你要说明这个服务是何种类型的
It is better to customize those labels to specific
总之 让你的导航栏有一个清晰的定位
items that you are providing within your website.
是比较重要的
Another commonly used pattern for
接下来我想介绍一个常见的
providing navigational information within a website is what we call as a breadcrumb.
设计导航的图样 路径导航
If you have noticed on many websites, at the top, you might see a set of
事实上 如今很多网站的抬头处 都有一系列的链接
links being indicated with pointers to sublinks.
这些链接之间可能会有一个 小箭头来起承接作用
And the current page that you are on might be highlighted in that set of links.
然后当前页面对应的链接 往往会在这一系列链接中高亮表示
Clicking on any one of those earlier links will take you back within the hierarchy.
如果你点击这一串链接中的一个 它将将你导航到对应的网页
So, in some sense, the breadcrumbs sort of also
你应该可以发现 路径导航在一定程度上
reflects some kind of a structure of your web page.
反映了你网站的架构
Now, there are many different ways of designing breadcrumbs.
能应用路径导航的场合有很多
If you have a website where people are going through a step-by-step process,
其一为在用户进行 一步一步的操作的场合
say, for example, purchasing an airline ticket, the breadcrumbs might indicate
比如说网购一张飞机票
the current sequence within the entire set of steps that the user is at the moment.
那么路径导航就是向用户表明流程进度的 很好的一个工具
Or if you have a e-commerce website, you might have a current sequence of steps
又或是在一个电子商务网站上 用户可能会要经历一系列的步骤来
in order to order an item or a set of items from that company.
购买一个或一些物品 那么使用路径导航也是好的选择
So you might indicate, for example, whether the user is currently in
比如说用户可能需要知道
the selection process of the items, or the user is in the payment process, and so on.
他现在是处于选择商品的时期 还是付款的时期 之类的
So, that is what we have addressed,
总结地说就是 路径导航有几种用法
path based navigation support within the breadcrumbs.
其一是用在注重访问路径的地方
The second approach would be to provide a location based information
其二是用在层次导航
within the breadcrumb hierarchy.
其三是用在有线性平行项目的地方
A third alternative that you might have seen in some websites,
比如说在一个电子商务网站上
where the breadcrumbs are not actually indicated as a linear sequence but
你可以通过路径导航
more like a set of choices, maybe where you have several set of attributes related
来告诉用户整个流程中的
to the items that you might be selecting on an e-commerce website.
一个个步骤
Say, for example, a price range, the color, or the size,
比如说 价格 颜色 又或大小
or the type, or maybe the manufacturer's information, and so on.
又或类型 总之是一系列的信息
So those kind of things that can also form information that
这一串线性平行项目
could be characterized under breadcrumbs.
就可以用路径导航来组织
Let's take an example of your own course website
让我们在我们的课程网站中
to see how breadcrumbs are being used there.
来看看路径导航是怎么样的吧
For example, when you visit your own course page,
比如说 在我们的课程网站这里
as you are going through the various items
当你连续点进了若干个链接
in the course content, you would notice on the top
你可以看到在抬头这里
a breadcrumb based navigation that is already provided for you.
就有一个路径导航
In there, we have the upper level links
在这路径导航中
being shown in the breadcrumbs as links and the current location
有一系列的看上去 像是链接一样的东西
being shown just by information, and it is not a link, but
这些东西告诉了你一些信息
just identifying where you are currently in the hierarchy.
它们不是真正的链接 不过向你阐述了 该网站的层次结构
There are several other navigation aids that are used in practice.
在实际应用中 还有许多其它的 辅助导航的东西
These include tabs, pills, pagination.
比如说标签页 胶囊式标签页 页码标注等
Especially when you have a lot of information to be shown to a user,
特别是当你有一大堆信息 要呈现给用户时
you might actually subdivide it into pages, and
你可能需要将这坨信息分成好几页
then let the user access the information page by page.
然后通过某种方式让用户 在这几页间浏览
So you would provide some kind of pagination support at either the top or
那么此时页码标注就是个好的辅助工具
the bottom of the page of information that you are displaying.
它能在抬头亦或页尾处提醒用户 当前页面是第几页
We have dropdowns, accordions, tags,
我们还有下拉菜单 折叠 标签
Scrollspy, and Affix, and many others.
滚动监听 附加导航 等等其它的工具
We will look at some of these in more details in subsequent
我们将会在接下来的某几节课中
modules of this course.
详细学习其中的一些工具 【翻译 - Carefree0910】